hey there what's up coaches mentors and
trainers my name is Jeremiah Kowski and
in this podcast I talk about how you can
grow your business get more clients and
reach those goals that you have so you
can start making six figures now today
on the grow Your Life podcast I want to
talk about something that I think is
really going to help you if you feel
stuck in your own business I was having
a client conversation with one of my
one-on-one clients and we're talking
about this in in her own life in her own
business as to why she was stuck and
feeling like she couldn't make six
figures there's two things that I
believe are so important you need to
believe that you can actually make the
six figures that you want to make in
your business you need to be able to
have the faith and belief that it's
possible for you if you don't you're not
going to be able to reach it because
you're coming from a place where you
don't think that that is even possible
so you're literally fighting an uphill
battle waiting for something outside of
you to validate to you that it's
possible so that's one of the first
things to realize that the belief that
it's possible comes from within and if
you have other competing beliefs or
behaviors or experiences in your
environment around you that are stopping
that and changing that belief you need
to make sure to address those now the
other one is this is that we often times
worry way too much about other people's
approval now it's not that we're going
to go out there and do stuff to to to
mess up or to have people dislike us or
to disapprove of us no we would never do
that on purpose but in the process of
you actually building your business to
reach your goals to go
accomplish the things that you want to
accomplish you're going to drop some
balls you're going to make some mistakes
and you might be listening to this right
now saying well not me I wouldn't I'm
not capable of that I can't it's just
not possible for Me Maybe for you
Jeremiah I want you to understand this
I've worked with thousands of coaches
and mentors that there is a thing in
your brain that is literally telling you
that you need to do everything perfect
that everything you do you can't mess up
you can't make a mistake and whatever
that thing is it usually comes from past
experiences where when you made a
mistake things didn't go how you want
and we want to end up controlling them
to make them go how we want and so
listen I want your success that's the
thing I want you to be
successful but one of the biggest things
that blocks us from being successful is
perfectionism and the need for other
people's total acceptance and approval
as you go out there to build your
business the more success you have the
less approval that you will have from
other people outside of
you I'm going to say that again the more
success that you have the less approval
at each level that you have from people
outside of you because what ends up
happening is is that the people in your
life that you normally found acceptance
and approval from they're going to drop
off they're going to disappear they're
not going to want to spend time in your
space
anymore and that's something that we
need to be okay
with something that I find a lot of
people they're hanging way too much onto
the past
experiences and
relationships that have actually held
them in captivity to the life that they
used to live preventing them from
stepping into the life that they want to
live you know I find that in my own life
anytime that I step into a new season at
a new level I have to change the people
that I'm listening to I can look back
even six months ago
big change started happening in my life
found out my wife was pregnant with our
Second
Son and uh
man I found there was literally a
handful of people that I was engaging
with spending a lot of time with talking
with that just were not healthy for me
to spend time with anymore and they were
always negative all the time they were
always a Debbie Downer about everything
everything everything if you find
yourself spending time around people
that are constantly negative and
pointing out the faults in things and
how they can't work
out those aren't your people and and and
I feel for those that those are those
that are closest to them okay you might
write this off because of that don't
please because you don't have to take in
what they're saying that's a choice to
do that because it's been a habit it's
been a behavior that you've done for a
long time is to take in what everybody
says
and hold on to it
tightly it's something that I had to
learn in my own life and in my own
business that you know what it's okay
for people to have a different opinion
of me than I do of
me and I don't need to change my
behavior because of
it and that's when you grow is when you
learn that it's okay and it's actually
by Design and a good thing and the other
thing is is this is that you start
living your life with expectation of
things going well for you you start
having a vision
of things going really good for you you
know we fear
disappointment so much that we let our
worry and fear of
disappointment of others disappointing
other people and our own selves being
disappointed lock us into a prison in
our own
minds you know I find I found myself
doing this for
years and I still catch myself sometimes
doing it
but I need you to realize this that for
you to be successful as a coach and as a
mentor in your marketing you got to let
that stuff go you got to lay that stuff
down that
idolatry of others
approval and their opinions that need
for everybody to think good things about
you there are people in your life that
think good things about you and even
them they don't always approve of
everything and that's
okay again it's not that you're going
out there to do things to get
disapproval from other people you're not
intentionally trying to be
disapproved or disliked by anybody in
fact you're you're doing all the right
things I think that's the key to realize
is that you get to be the one that
decides what the right things are not
everybody else around you in your
environment now I can tell you there's a
shift that happened in my own life
couple months ago where I found a new
level of this and and and as soon as I
started owning and believing in the
people that were loving what I was
talking about and I wasn't seeking the
approval and acceptance and of
everything that I did with those that
were closest around me even
family my life actually got a lot better
and you know what my relationships
actually got a lot better with family
cuz I didn't have to defend myself I
didn't start arguing debating trying to
prove myself self to
everybody you know I find that sometimes
especially if you grow up with faith
there's a twisted Bible verse Show
Yourself approved workmen that are not
ashamed gosh that verse got Twisted in
my head that I needed to be approved by
everybody and yet that's not even what
that means it's
crazy a approve of yourself know that
God approves of
you and then do the things that you know
are going to work best for
you not everybody is going
to be in
agreement on the same page with
everything you say and that's
okay and you can still make money in
your business if that happens because
here's what happens is that when you're
actually selling when you're actually
leading when you step into a leadership
role what we're talking about here is
going from a passive role where you are
an
observer experiencing life happening to
you to where you start actually being
the one that creates life around you and
you start creating the
experiences of people in your own life
we can't control other people we can't
and we work way too hard to do so
passively instead the best thing to do
is to start controlling yourself
deciding what you're going to do maybe I
do something right over here in my
business and and and certain people
don't like it but it's the best thing
for me that's great and that's how we
want to do
it and that's how a good coach shows up
because you're able to coach people not
based on trying to be the most liked
person but the one that does the right
thing and I think that that's key is to
redefine what we know as the right thing
and what is perfect because if I look
back in my my own
business I was constantly going based on
some sort of indicator of other people's
responses to me now yes when we're
marketing when we're optimizing I'm
optimizing a funnel strategy there's
certain things you can do that attract
more people than others but if you get
so caught up in trying to control what
other people do and how they show up
you're not going to make any money in
your business because you're going to be
in such you're going to be so deep in
the weeds
trying to make everything fit your
vision instead of just stepping back
letting go watching things happen and
you might say wait a sec Jeremiah that
sounds in conflict of what you just said
you said not to be an observer but to go
make it happen I'm telling you this
control
yourself not other
people okay what can you do what can you
take personal responsibility in and one
of the first ones to do is to become
okay
with other people may be not agreeing
with your
choices doing things in your life that
are best for you even if others don't
think they're the best right
now now again we don't want to be
Reckless and
destructive and we got to be mindful and
compassionate about how our actions
impact others of course don't hear me
out that I'm saying that you don't do
that that's important it absolutely
is but you don't let it be your all
consuming
activity because often times that comes
from an inner child that was trying to
create a safe environment when they felt
like everything was unsafe around them
or maybe you were a teenager who felt
unsafe because of everybody around you
who disliked you in school or maybe in a
corporate job you got bullied or in a
church where you got abused or
mistreated and I can tell you this being
mistreated for years by other people IT
wires your
brain to feel like okay I have to seek
approval and I can tell you this until
you shift that until you change those
wired connections and I I will say it's
painful mentally emotionally even
sometimes physically can be painful in
your gut you're going to feel like
you're doing the wrong thing even though
you know it's the right
thing and learning to discern between
the two you know some ways that really
help alleviate this is that if we look
at in our own life a couple of things
how are we
eating how are you taking care of your
physical body are you are you eating
green vegetables are you are you
drinking enough water are you getting
enough sleep are you having a lot of
alcohol or caffeine or or nicotine or or
or CBD oil or whatever that is you know
I found myself in my own life throughout
the years drinking too much having too
much coffee things like that the other
day I had some I had some caffeine in
and it and it and it made me anxious for
like 2 days and I realized wow this was
the state that I used to live in
constantly especially if you're somebody
who's very empathic and a Feeler and you
can feel things a
lot you'll end up picking up stuff
that's not even really going on because
your brain starts making up stuff as far
as that goes and so that's one of the
things to do is to not project the worst
case scenario but to start to EXP expect
the best case of how you want things to
go for you and you start having a vision
and visualizing the expectation of great
things happening in your life great
things happening for you and this might
be one of the hardest things that you
ever do is visualize great things
happening for you but it's going to
shift everything not just as okay I
visualized it and it didn't happen but
you literally get into a feeling and a
belief system where you believe that
these things are going to happen that
they are going to come together that
things are going to work out in your
favor and you really own it to your
core to believe those things it shifts
everything shifts your
environment changes the atmosphere
around you and now you become a conduit
for great things to
happen Okay so I want to encourage you
if you're somebody right now who's
building a business
and you and you've been struggling
you've been feeling
stuck this might be what I just talked
about this
process of getting yourself excited
about the great things that are going to
happen well what if I do them and they
don't work
out great awesome means something better
is on the
way and start believing that that when
things don't go how I want or need them
in that
moment that control Factor
goodness but we do that and we do it
passive
aggressively and we do it
nicely realizing that maybe just maybe
something better is actually on the
way and you start believing that and you
start having faith
in the things you're doing and the
places you're going and the people
you're talking to and the environments
that you're in and the books you're
reading and the actions you're
taking and you start watching certain
synchronicities happen around you that
weren't happening
before what's beautiful is that you end
up training your reticular activating
system in this you know I talked about
the ra a couple weeks back on this one
thing that I noticed is that if I get my
brain way too focused on negativity you
know I I got bit up by some mosquitoes
outside in my backyard and if all I
focused on was that my whole body starts
itching it's amazing it's incredible how
my body does that but I tried to just
shift my focus away from that and focus
on something else for a little while is
the irritation there sure maybe a little
bit but it's not the only thing that I'm
focusing on and even as I'm talking
about this right now like I'm starting
to feel a little bit in my feet and
stuff like that it's because our brain
is a powerful thing that literally
creates and an experience with hormones
and chemicals and all of this in our
neurotransmitters in our body and they
amplify whatever we put our mind focus
on and I'm not talking about just an
observation but a real tangible Focus
whatever you put that focus on what are
you if you're trying to avoid bad things
happening this is why a lot of times
when people are so focused on making
sure that thing that bad things don't
happen and and that all that happens
they end up experiencing a lot of those
negative things because literally their
energy is just looking for the next bad
thing to
happen instead of focusing in on how
everything's going great for you and
gratitude and it shifts you into
literally your brain wires itself
differently to start noticing the good
stuff and then you start doing the good
stuff and then you start experiencing
the good
life that is possible for everybody I
truly believe but the biggest battle we
face is right between our are two ears
you know I worked with a therapist for
about 3 years and we were able to
process through a lot of different deep
seated emotions and things like that and
now I got to the point where I'm like
you know what I don't need to keep
replaying the past because I'm creating
a future that is beautiful for me and my
family and that lights me on fire I'm so
excited every single
day and you can experience the same
thing as well you just got to choose
to this podcast can help you with that
the Environ that we have in my coaching
Community can help you with that if you
work with me oneon-one
I can help you with that to get you the
results that you're looking for as a
mentor as a trainer as a coach you don't
have to stay stuck you don't have to
experience the
hardship if you don't want to you can
literally choose to change your
situation and I listen I've been around
a lot of people that have had chronic
illnesses and they have told me you know
what I can either choose to focus how on
how crappy it is or how amazing my life
still is and they literally live a
better life than some people that are in
perfect health it's amazing because your
mind is a powerful
tool and if you exercise it in the
beginning it might be hard you might not
be used to it but it's like exercising a
muscle and that changes everything for
you all right listen if this has helped
you please share this with somebody
please pass this episode on I think it's
really going to impact others and I'd
love to work with you as well in your
business if you're a coach Mentor
trainer to get more clients in your
business this is one of those things
that's
foundational that I think will help you
accomplish great things we'll talk soon
everybody have a good one
[Music]